【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧
《老友记》蓝光版 第01季 第01集
字幕来源：射手网      调校制作：寒 枫
字幕编辑：菲衣粒粒 林奇先生
没什么好说的 他不过是我的同事
There's nothing to tell. It's just some guy I work with.
少来了 和你交往的男人
Come on. You're going out with a guy.
一定有问题
There's gotta be something wrong with him.
他有驼背么?有假发的驼子?
So does he have a hump and a hair piece?
慢着 他吃粉笔吗?
Wait. Does he eat chalk?
我只是不想你重蹈我和卡尔的覆辙
I don't want her to go through what I went through with Carl. Oh.
好吧 各位别急  这都算不上是约会
Okay, everybody relax. This is not even a date.
我们不过是出去吃个晚餐 不上床
It's just two people going out to dinner and not having sex.
听起来好像是说我的约会
Sounds like a date to me.
记得中学时代的梦
I'm back in high school, in the middle of the cafeteria
我站在自助餐厅 突然发现自己全身赤裸
and I realize I'm totally naked.
耶 我也做过那样的梦
Oh, yeah.I've had that dream.
然后我低头一看  看见有一支电话
Then I look down and I realize there is a phone
在那儿
there.
而不是?       没错
Instead of         That's right!
我没做过那样的梦      没
-That one, I've never had.        No.
突然 那个电话响了
All of a sudden, the phone starts to ring.
竟然是我妈妈打来的
And it turns out it's my mother.
这十分怪 因为 她从来不打电话给我!
Which is very, very weird because she never calls me.
嗨
Hi.
这家伙说"嗨"的时候 我总想杀了我自己
This guy says "hello," I wanna kill myself.
你还好吧 老哥?
Are you okay, sweetie?
我就感觉好像某人伸手进我的喉咙
I just feel like someone grabbed my small intestine
抓住我的小肠 从我的嘴里拉出来
pulled it out of my mouth
再在我的脖子上打结       要饼干吗?
and tied it around my neck.         Cookie?
卡箩今天搬走了她的东西
Carol moved her stuff out today.
天呐
Oh.
我给你拿咖啡       谢谢
Let me get you some coffee.         Thanks.
额
Ew.Unh.
不 不要! 不要打掉我的灵气
No. No,don't! Stop cleansing my aura.
别管它了 好吗?
Just leave my aura alone,okay?
我会没事的 好吧?
I'll be fine. All right?
真的 各位 我希望她开心
Really. I hope she'll be very happy.
不 你不会的      没错
No, you don't.         No, I don't.
去她的 她甩的我
To hell with her. She left me!
而且你一直都不知道她是Les
And you never knew she was a lesbian.
没有行了吧?
No! Okay?
为什么你们总是提起那件事呢?
Why does everyone keep fixating on that?
连她都不知道 我怎么会知道
She didn't know. How should I know?
有时真希望自己也是个Les
Sometimes I wish I was a lesbian.
我刚刚大声说出来了吗?
Did I say that out loud?
别闷闷不乐了 罗斯
All right, Ross. Look, you're feeling a lot of pain right now.
你一肚子火 心如刀割
You're angry. You're hurting.
让我来告诉你解决之道
Can I tell you what the answer is?
你该去(脱衣舞场)找乐子去
Strip joints!
你单身 有性需求
Come on, you're single. Have some hormones.
我说 并不是我想单身的
See, but I don't want to be single, okay?
我只想再结婚
I just wanna be married again.
我只想要一百万
And I just want a million dollars!
瑞秋?
Rachel?
天啊 莫妮卡 谢天谢地
Oh, God, Monica! Hi! Thank God!
我到过你的住处 你不在
I went to your building and this guy with a hammer said
有个拿着一根大榔头的人说你可能会在这儿
that you might be here
结果你真的在这儿
and you are.
想来杯咖啡吗?       无咖啡因的
Can I get you some coffee?         Decaf.
各位 她叫瑞秋
Okay, everybody, this is Rachel.
另一位从林肯高中生存下来的人
Another Lincoln High survivor.
这位叫钱德勒  菲比 乔伊
This is everybody. This is Chandler and Phoebe and Joey.
还记得我哥罗斯吗?
And remember my brother, Ross?
当然       嗨
Sure!         Hey.
嗨       偶买糕的
Hi.         Oh, God.
你是想现在告诉我们
So you wanna tell us now,
还是等你的伴娘来?
or are we waiting for four wet bridesmaids?
呃 好吧 婚礼前半个小时发生了变数
Oh, God! Well, it started about a half-hour before the wedding.
我在堆放礼物的房间里
I was in this room with all the presents
看着船形卤肉盘
and I was looking at this gravy boat.
非常漂后的船形卤肉盘
This really gorgeous Limoges gravy boat.
突然间 低脂糖?
When all of a sudden Sweet 'N Low?
我意识到
I realized
船形卤肉盘比巴瑞更能引起我的"性趣"
I was more turned on by this gravy boat than by Barry.
当我意识到巴瑞愈看愈像薯头先生时
Then I got really freaked out, and that's when it hit me:
我自己都吓了一跳
How much Barry looks like Mr. Potato Head.
我是说 我一直都认为他很眼熟
You know, I mean, I always knew he looked familiar, but
总之 我必须离开 我开始想
Anyway, I just had to get out of there, and I started wondering:
我为何这么做? 我为谁这样做?
Why am I doing this? and Who am I doing this for?
于是我不知该走往何处
Anyway, I just didn't know where to go,
我知道你我日渐疏远
and I know you and I have drifted apart
但是你是我在这个城市 认识的唯一一个人
but you're the only person I know in the city.
也是唯一没受邀参加婚礼的人
Who wasn't invited to the wedding.
这件事就甭提啦
Oh, I was kind of hoping that wouldn't be an issue.
我猜他送她一台管风琴
I'm guessing he bought her the big pipe organ
她肯定不喜欢
and she's really not happy about it.
爸 我不能嫁给他
Daddy, I just I can't marry him.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是不爱他
I just don't love him.
对 是我的问题
Well, it matters to me.
她不该穿那条裤子
She should not be wearing those pants.
我建议把她推下去
I say push her down the stairs.
推她下楼 推她下楼 推她下楼
Push her down the stairs! Push her down the stairs!
爸 你听我说
Come on, Daddy, listen to me!
大家这样评价我这一辈子 你是一只鞋
It's like all of my life, everyone's always told me, You're a shoe!
你是一只鞋
You're a shoe! You're a shoe! You're a shoe!
今天我倒想看看如果我不再是鞋会怎样
Then today I stopped and said, What if I don't wanna be a shoe?
我说如果我想当皮包呢?
What if I wanna be a purse? You know?
或是帽子呢?
Or a hat?
不 我不需你帮我买帽子 我说我是一顶帽子
I don't want you to buy me a hat, I am a hat.
爸 这是一种比喻
It's a metaphor, Daddy!
你看他也有些问题
You can see where he'd have trouble.
爸 这是我的人生
Look, Daddy, it's my life.
或许我会和莫妮卡住在这儿
Well, maybe I'll just stay here with Monica.
我想我们已确定好谁要和莫妮卡住在这儿
I guess we've established she's staying with Monica.
或许那是我的决定
Well, maybe that's my decision.
或许我不希罕你的钱
Well, maybe I don't need your money.
等一下 等一下 我说的是或许
Wait! Wait! I said maybe!
深呼吸 就这样
Okay. Just breathe, that's it.
试着想着美好的事物
Just try to think of nice, calm things.
玫瑰上的雨滴 猫嘴上的胡须
Raindrops on roses And whiskers on kittens
门铃和雪橇之类的
Doorbells and sleigh bells And something with mittens
啦啦啦 还有手套
Lalala something With string
我现在好多了
I'm all better now.
我的功劳
I helped.
哎 这可能是件好事呢!
Look, this is probably for the best, you know?
要自立 决定自己的事情
Independence. Taking control of your life.
嗨 如果你需要什么尽管来找我好了
And, hey, if you need anything, you can always come to Joey.
我和钱德勒就住在对面
Me and Chandler live right across the hall.
而且他经常不在家
And he's away a lot.
你别挑逗她了 今天可是她的结婚之日
Joey, stop hitting on her. It's her wedding day.
怎么啦?难道还有什么明文规定不成?
What? Like there's a rule or something?
别再这样 声音很刺耳
Please don't do that again. It's a horrible sound.
我是保罗天啊      让他进来
Uh, it's Paul.         Buzz him in.
保罗是谁?      调酒的那个保罗?
Who's Paul?         Paul, the wine guy, Paul?
或许吧
Maybe.
等等 你今晚该不是真的要和
Wait a minute. Your 'not a real date'
调酒的那个保罗约会吧?
is with Paul, the wine guy?
他终于开口约你了?对
He finally asked you out?         Yes.
终于被你等到了
Ooh. This is a Dear Diary moment.
瑞秋 你看 我可以取消
Rach, wait, I can cancel.
不用了 你去吧 我不会有事的
Please, no. Go, I'll be fine.
罗斯 你没事吧 你要我留下来吗?
Ross, are you okay? I mean, do you want me to stay?
那样最好
That'd be good.
真的吗?
Really?
假的 去吧是保罗 调酒师耶
No, go on! It's Paul, the wine guy.
请进 保罗 这位是
Hi,come in. Paul, this is
各位 各位 他就是保罗
everybody. Everybody, this is Paul.
保罗 调酒大师
Paul, the wine guy.
调酒大师      抱歉 我没听清楚你名字 保罗 是吗?
Wine guy.         I didn't catch your name. Paul, was it?
换衣服请坐 两秒钟
Okay. Sit down. Two seconds.
我刚拔掉四根睫毛 不妙
Ooh, I just pulled out four eyelashes. That can't be good.
瑞秋 你打算如何渡过今晚?
So, Rachel, what are you up to tonight?
我应该在前往阿鲁巴渡蜜月的途中
Well, I was supposed to be headed for Aruba on my honeymoon
因此没了
so, nothing.
我懂 你没去渡蜜月
Right. You're not even getting your honeymoon.
虽然阿鲁巴在此时
God. No, no. Although, Aruba. Heh. This time of year? Eh.
有很多
Talk about your
大蜥蜴
big lizards.
如果你今晚不想独处
Anyway, if you don't feel like being alone tonight
乔伊和钱德勒要到我那儿帮我组合新家俱
Joey and Chandler are helping me with my furniture.
对 我们都相当兴奋
Yes, and we're very excited about it.
谢谢 但我今晚想待在这儿
Actually, thanks, but I'm just gonna hang out here tonight.
我折磨了一天        好吧 当然
It's been a long day.         Oh, sure. Okay. Sure.
菲比 想帮忙吗?
Hey, Pheebs, you wanna help?
我可以去  但我不想去
Oh, I wish I could, but I don't want to.
我应该用蜗杆
I'm supposed to attach a brackety thing to the side things
将托架装在侧面
using a bunch of these little worm guys.
但我没看见托架和蜗杆
I have no brackety thing, I see no worm guys whatsoever
而且 我的脚好麻
and I cannot feel my legs.
这是什么?
What's this?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
书架做好了        终于做好了
Done with the bookcase.         All finished.
这是卡罗最爱喝的啤酒
This was Carol's favorite beer.
从易拉罐里喝 我早应该看出蛛丝马迹
She always drank it out of the can. I should have known.
罗斯 我问你一个问题
Hey. Ross, let me ask you a question.
她分得家俱 音响和好电视
She got the furniture, the stereo, the good TV.
你分得什么?
What did you get?
你们
You guys.
天啊       你昏头了吧
Oh, God. Oh, my God.         You got screwed.
嗯 天啊      我知道 我是个大白痴
Oh, my God.         I know, I know. I'm such an idiot.
她每周看四五次牙医时我就该了解
I should've caught on when she went to the dentist four and five times a week.
我指牙齿能有多干净?
I mean, how clean can teeth get?
我哥正承受着这种痛苦  一副失魂落魄的样子
My brother's going through that. He's such a mess.
你是怎么熬过来的?
How did you get through it?
你可以不小心砸烂她贵重的东西 比如她的
He might try accidentally breaking something valuable of hers.
她的         腿?
Say her         Leg?
这样也不赖我
Heh. That's one way of going through it, yeah.
我砸烂了她的表
Me, I went for the watch.
你真的砸烂过她的表?         对啊
You actually broke her watch?         Mm.
巴瑞 真是对不起
Barry, I'm sorry. I am so sorry.
你一定认为此事与我那次说的话有关
You probably think it's about
关于你做爱时穿着袜子 其实不是
making love with your socks on, but it isn't.
问题出在我身上 我
It isn't, it's about me. And I
答录机又把我挂断了 不管怎样
Hi. Machine cut me off again. Anyway
你知道最可怕的是什么?
You know what's scary?
要是每个人只能有一个女人?
What if there's only one woman for everybody?
我是说 要是你找到一个女人(做另一半)
I mean, what if you get one woman,
然后就不能在找了?
and that's it?
不幸的是 我这件事里
Unfortunately, in my case,
那个一个女人是给"她"准备的
there was only one woman for her.
你在说什么?一个女人
What are you talking about? One woman.
那就像在说你只能吃一种口味的冰淇淋
That's like saying there's only one flavor of ice cream for you.
罗斯 告诉你吧  冰淇淋的口种有千百种
Let me tell you something, Ross. There's lots of flavors out there.
有各种点心糖果冰淇淋
There's rocky road and cookie dough and bing cherry vanilla.
你可以加上小糖条或是核果  或是奶油
You can get them with jimmies or nuts or whipped cream.
这是你一生中最美好的事
This is the best thing that ever happened to you.
你八岁时就结婚了吧?
You got married. You were like, what, 8?
欢迎来到世界 抓住勺子
Welcome back to the world. Grab a spoon.
我真的不知道自己是饥渴还是欲火焚身?
I honestly don't know if I'm hungry or horny.
那么就别碰我家的冰箱
Then stay out of my freezer.
自从她甩掉我之后我
Ever since she walked out on me, I
什么?
What? What?
什么 你打算边嚼面条边讲?
You wanna spell it out with noodles?
不 这就像是"第五次约会真情告白"
No, it's more of a fifth date kind of revelation.
有第五次约会?
Oh, so there's gonna be a fifth date?
不需要吗?
Isn't there?
需要 我想需要的
Yeah, yeah. I think there is.
你刚才想说什么?
What were you gonna say?
这个 呃
Well Er, uh
自从她离开后
Ever since she left me, um
我就一直无法 没做过
I haven't been able to perform
爱
sexually.
天啊 天啊 对不起 对不起
Oh, God! Oh, God! I am soI'm so sorry.
没关系
It's okay.
你现在需要的应该不是让人吐口水吧
Being spit on is probably not what you need right now.
多久了?
How long?
两年了
Two years.
哇
Wow!
真高兴你砸烂了她的表
I'm glad you smashed her watch.
你还想要第五次约会?
So you still think you might want that fifth date?
当然想
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
我乔安妮愿意嫁给查尔斯
I, Joanie, take you, Charles
为我的终身伴侣
as my lawful husband.
你是否愿意让乔乔安妮      喔 看
Do you take Joanie?         Oh! See.
乔安妮爱的是恰棋
But Joanie loved Chachi.
差别就在这儿
That's the difference.
抓住勺子
"Grab a spoon."
知道我等着"抓这把勺子"等了多久吗?
Do you know long it's been since I grabbed a spoon?
那"比利 不要成为一个英雄"
Do the words, "Billy, don't be a hero,"
这个故事对你有何启发?
mean anything to you?
(著名反战歌 罗斯把找新女友比喻成上战场)
就算我鼓起勇气
You know, here's the thing. Even if I could get it together enough
约女人出去
to ask a woman out
但我要约谁呀?
who am I gonna ask?
神奇吧?我这辈子从没泡过咖啡
Isn't this amazing?
我这辈子从没泡过咖啡
I mean, I have never made coffee before in my life.
真神奇      恭喜了
That is amazing.        Congratulations.
如果你兴致大发想做蛋饼
While you're on a roll, if you feel like you gotta make a Western omelet or something
老实说我不太饿
Although, actually I'm really not that hungry this morning.
早安 早安
Good morning. Good morning.
Morning. Morning.
早安      早安 保罗
Morning.         Morning, Paul.
你好 保罗       嗨 保罗 是吗?
Hello, Paul.         Hi. Paul, is it?
昨晚真是太棒了
I had a really great time last night.
谢谢你太谢谢你了
Thank you.Thank you so much.
晚点打电话      好的
We'll talk later, okay?        Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
那还不叫约会?
That wasn't a real date.
那你真正的约会到底干些什么?
What the hell do you do on a real date?
闭嘴 把桌子抬回去      好吧
Shut up and put my table back.        Okay.
孩子们 我要上班去了
All right, kids, I gotta get to work.
如果我不输入那些数字 也没什么关系
If I don't input those numbers, it doesn't make much of a difference.
你们大伙儿都有工作?
So, like, you guys all have jobs?
对 我们都有工作
Yeah, we all have jobs.
这样才有钱买东西
See, that's how we buy stuff.
对 我是个演员
Yeah, I'm an actor.
我见过你吗?
Wow. Would I have seen you in anything?
大概没见过吧
Oh, I doubt it.
我大部份都是在地区性的节目中演出
Mostly regional work.
等等 除非你看过皮诺曹的重播
Unless you happened to catch the Wee One's production of Pinocchio.
瞧 盖佩多 我是个活生生的小男孩
"Look, Geppeto. I'm a real live boy."
我不会理睬这种羞辱
I will not take this abuse.
你说得对 抱歉
You're right. I'm sorry.
"我曾是个小木偶 小木偶 "
Once I was a wooden boy A little wooden boy
今天感觉如何? 睡得还好吧?
So how are you doing today? Did you sleep okay?
和巴瑞通过电话吗? 我无法停止笑
Did you talk to Barry? I can't stop smiling.
我看得出来
I can see that.
你好像嘴里有一个衣架把嘴撑住了
You look like you slept with a hanger in your mouth.
我知道 他是那么
I know. He's just so
还记得你和东尼戴马克?
Remember you and Tony De Marco?
当然！     就像那样那样感觉
Oh,yeah!      Well, it's like that. With feelings.
你惹上麻烦了
Oh, wow, are you in trouble!
我要清醒 去工作
Okay, okay. I am just going to get up, go to work
整天都不想他
and not think about him all day.
或者只是清醒然后去工作
Or else I'm just gonna get up and go to work.
祝我幸运      为什么?
Oh, wish me luck!        What for?
我要去找工作
I'm gonna go get one of those job things.
嗨 莫妮卡      法兰妮 欢迎回来
Hey, Monica.         Hey, Franny. Welcome back.
佛罗里达如何?
How was Florida?
你们上床了 对不?
You had sex, didn't you?
你怎么看出来的?
How do you do that?
那么和谁呀? 认识保罗吗?
You know Paul.
保罗 那个调酒的?
Paul, the wine guy?
对 我认识保罗
Oh, yeah, I know Paul.
你认识保罗像我认识他一样?
You mean, you know Paul like I know Paul?
开玩笑 他还得谢我呢
Are you kidding? I take credit for Paul.
遇到我之前他已有两年没做爱了
Before me, there was no snap in his turtle for two years.
显然他是骗你的
Of course it was a line.
为什么? 为什么会有人那样做?
Why? Why would anybody do something like that?
我想答案比
We're looking for an answer more sophisticated than:
"设法骗你上床"更复杂
"To get you into bed."
问题出在我身上?
Is it me?
难道我有特殊气味
Is it like I have some sort of beacon that only dogs
只有狗和感情有严着问题的男人才闻得到
and men with severe emotional problems can hear?
过来 脚给我
All right, come here. Give me your feet.
我以为他是个好男人
I just thought he was nice, you know?
我无法相信你不懂这是骗局
I can't believe you didn't know it was a line.
猜猜看?
Guess what.
你找到工作了?      开玩笑?
You got a job?         Are you kidding?
我书都白念了
I'm trained for nothing.
今天的十二个面试全泡汤了
I was laughed out of 12 interviews today.
不过你却异常兴奋
Yet you're surprisingly upbeat.
换成是你 你也会一样
Well, you would be too
如果你遇见John and David的皮靴
if you found Joan and David boots on sale
打五折
50 percent off.
你真是太了解我了
Oh, how well you know me.
这是我的新皮靴  我不需要工作 不需要父母
They're my new "I don't need a job or my parents.
因为我有新皮靴
I've got great boots" boots.
你怎么付钱?      信用卡啊
How'd you pay for them?         Uh, credit card.
卡费谁费?
And who pays for that?
我爸
Um, my father.
成熟点 你不能靠你爸一辈子
You can't live off your parents your whole life.
我知道 所以我选择结婚
I know that. That's why I was getting married.
饶了她吧 第一次独立并不轻松
Give her a break. It's hard being on your own for the first time.
谢谢      不客气
Thank you.         You're welcome.
我记得我第一次来到纽约时的情况
I remember when I first came to this city,
当时我十四岁
I was 14.
我妈刚自杀  我继父再度入狱
My mom had killed herself and my stepdad was back in prison.
我在这儿人生地不熟
And I got here, and I didn't know anybody.
最后我和患白化症的男人同居
I ended up living with this albino guy
他为港务局的人清洗车窗
who was cleaning windshields outside Port Authority.
后来他自杀了
And then he killed himself.
然后我找到芳香按摩治疗的工作
And then I found aromatherapy.
所以请相信我你的心情我能体会
So believe me, I know exactly how you feel.
你需要的是
The word you're looking for is:
无论如何
"Anyway"
好的 准备好了吗?
All right. You ready?
不不 不 我没准备好      别磨蹭了
I don't think so.        Oh, come on.
来 剪 剪 剪 剪
Cut. Cut.
Cut, cut, cut.
嘿 太好吧
Hey. All right.
欢迎来到现实的世界
Welcome to the real world.
糟透了 但你会喜欢的
It sucks. You're gonna love it.
好 就到这 你要睡在沙发上吗?
Well, that's it. You gonna crash on the couch?
不 我要回家       你没事吧?
No. No, I gotta go home sometime.         Are you gonna be okay?
还好
Yeah.
嗨 看我在地板上发现什么?
Look what I just found on the floor.
什么?
What?
那是保罗的手表
That's Paul's watch.
放回原地就好了
You can just put it back where you found it.
好晚安 各位
Oh, boy. All right. Good night, everybody.
晚安
Good night.
嗯      嗯
Hmm.         Hmm.
对不起      不 不 不 你来
Oh, sorry.         No. Oh, no. Go.
吃吧 我不饿      平分它?
No, have it, really.         Split it?
好吧      好的
Okay.         Okay.
谢谢
Thanks.
你大概不知道我在高中时
You probably didn't know this, but back in high school I had
对你一见钟情
a major crush on you.
我知道
I knew.
你知道?
You did? Oh.
我总想你认为我不过是莫妮卡的书呆子哥哥
I figured you thought I was Monica's geeky older brother.
没错      哦
I did.         Oh.
听着 你觉得
Listen, do you think
如果抛开其他不好的因素
And try not to let my vulnerability become any kind of a factor here.
我能偶尔约你出去吗?有时?有可能?
Do you think it would be okay if I ask you out sometime, maybe?
可以
Yeah.
可能
Maybe.
好的
Okay.
或许我会的
Okay, maybe I will.
晚安       晚安
Good night.         Good night.
明天见
See you.
嗯
Mm-hm.
等等 你怎么了?
Wait, wait. Hey, what's with you?
我刚"抓住了勺子"
I just grabbed a spoon.
我真不敢相信我的耳朵
Can't believe what I'm hearing.
我是说你...      我是说你...
What I said you had         What I said you had
你有完没完?      我的老毛病又犯了?
Would you stop?         Oh, was I doing it again?
没错
Yes.
谁要喝咖啡?
Would anybody like more coffee?
你煮的还只是端过来而已?
Did you make it or are you just serving it?
端来而已       好 好 给我来杯咖啡
I'm just serving it.        I'll have a cup of coffee.
孩子们 新梦
Kids, new dream.
我在拉斯维加斯  我是丽莎米内利
I'm in Las Vegas. I'm Liza Minnelli.
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-==http://www.hdmeiju.com==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧